Sri Sainee Thirumurugan

Email: srisainee2310@gmail.com

Mobile: +61 413 931 624

Portfolio: https://littlebravesri.github.io/

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/sri-sainee-thirumurugan/

GitHub: https://github.com/littlebravesri

Career Objective

Master of Data Science graduate having well developed teamwork, communication and problem-solving skills broadened during academic and work experience. Possessing extensive knowledge in Python, R, SQL, PowerBI and Azure through experience and projects. Confident about actively engaging in a dynamic and challenging environment to develop personal growth while contributing to the organization's success.

Education

Master of Data Science – RMIT University

Bachelor of Engineering (Computer Science and Engineering) – Anna University

July 2019 – June 2021

August 2015- May 2019

Certifications

Microsoft Student Accelerator program 2021September 2021KPMG Virtual Data Analytics internshipSeptember 2021Microsoft Azure fundamentalsJune 2021The Sparks FoundationOctober 2020

Work Experience

Data Analyst October 2021 – current

Movember, Melbourne

- Developed PowerBI dashboards for the requesting departments' analysis and reporting real time insights on fundraisers and donors' demographics and performances.
- Utilized Power Query and DAX to create measures and metrics required for visualization.
- Analyzed and researched donors' data for strategic development of engagement in programs and retention.
- Imported data from Amazon S3 and PostgreSQL servers into Python for Post Campaign Analysis.
- Performed ad-hoc analysis with SQL queries on DBeaver to find the number of registrations, active rates, average donation amount etc.
- Presented the story of fundraisers throughout the campaign in the dashboard to the internal stakeholders.
- Published dashboards in PowerBI with refresh schedules and provided access to stakeholders within the organization.

Skills: PowerBI, Python, PostgreSQL, Data Visualization, Data Analysis, Amazon AWS.

Data and Analytics Officer

August 2021 – September 2021

Dementia Australia, Melbourne

- Identified different tags and triggers used in the forms via Google Tag Manager and Google Analytics to report of tracking activities such as link clicks and PDF downloads.
- Explored different marketing tools like MailChimp, Eventbrite, Formstack, Google Analytics to collect data for the purpose of visualization.
- Used Zapier to integrate the marketing tools to Google Sheets and created zaps to automate the addition of new or updated data into Google Sheets.
- Imported the data from Google sheets into PowerBI and created various visualization as per the requirement of the marketing team.
- Documented the data preprocessing steps and data transformation performed in PowerBI.

• Delivered the visualization with a story to the marketing team to understand the monthly performance of their marketing websites.

Skills: PowerBI, Python, Story-telling, Agile/Scrum, Zapier, Google Sheets.

Data Analyst April 2021- July 2021

Wings CyberSpace International, Geelong

- Performed web scrapping on eBay using BeautifulSoup, Scrappy, ParseHub and Octoparse.
- Automated the web scrapping program to scrape multiple depth levels within a page.
- Carried out Data Preprocessing to clean the data for visualization.
- Designed dashboards using PowerBI and Tableau with data extracted from eBay.

Skills: Python. PowerBI, Tableau. Scrappy, BeautifulSoup, ParseHub.

Data Scientist November 2020 – January 2021

Know your terms, Melbourne

- Extracted text from web pages using Beautiful Soup and Scrapy.
- Mined text from PDF and docx files for displaying relevant terms and conditions for the users.
- Worked in an Agile/Scrum environment.

Skills: Python, Scrappy, BeautifulSoup, Agile/Scrum

Academic Experience

AI Powered Voice Assistance using Alexa

March 2021 – May 2021

RMIT Cyber Ready Cloud Innovation Centre – The Museum of London

- Developed custom skills for Alexa using Python in Alexa Development Console.
 - Integrated Trello Board with Alexa to read and update a card.
 - Deployed skills in Alexa skill store.
 - Attended multiple AWS workshops on building customer centric solutions.

Skills: API calls, AWS, Python, Requirement Elicitation and Documentation

Modelling Recyclable Materials Collected and Recycled of Victoria

March 2021 - June 2021

Work Integrated Learning – Sustainability Victoria

- Responsible for data collection of kurbside recycle materials of each Victorian council.
- Performed Data Preprocessing to clean the data sets.
- Designed various Machine Learning models such as Linear Regressions, Exponential Smoothing,
 XGBoost etc. to forecast future values of recycled materials.
- Designed Time Series models like ARIMA, FBprophet to predict future values of recycled materials.
- Assisted in creating the dashboard in Python to visualize the results of the models using Plotly.
- Documented the results of the models to compare and decide the best fit model for the data set.

Skills: Python, Data Analysis, Data Pre-processing, Data Visualization, Machine Learning, Time Series Analysis, Agile/Scrum

Crimes of Victoria Dashboard

May 2020 - June 2020

RMIT University

- Visualize crimes dataset in a dashboard showing the rate of crimes occurred during the years 2016-2019.
- Story telling of the crime rates of Victoria using Shiny and R interactive visualizations.
- Deployed dashboard in shinyapps.io:
 https://littlebravesri.shinyapps.io/Crimes/?_ga=2.186900512.902303536.1602752634-734726441.1602752634

Skills: R, Data Visualization, Shiny app

Additional Projects

Translating American Sign Language to Text and Speech

July 2021 - August 2021

Microsoft Student Accelerator Program 2021

• Developed and end-to-end AI solution using Microsoft Azure services.

- Trained Machine Learning model on ASL alphabets using Azure Cognitive Services and Machine Learning Studio.
- Created web app that accessed the web camera to predict and display the ASL alphabets.
- Used JavaScript's SpeechSynthesis library to convert the text to speech.
- Deployed the web app in Azure Power Apps.

Skills: Microsoft Azure, Flask, API calls, Python, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Machine Learning

Django Restful API Example Web App

April 2020 - May 2020

DataDisca Pyt Ltd

- Utilized Django Rest Framework to make API calls.
- Created routes to access model based and model less APIs.
- Created API calls to create, update, delete and print user and product information in SQLite database.

Skills: API calls, Django Rest Framework.